Oh no!
What do you understand?!
君に何が分かる
I will do anything to save those children!
あの子たちを救うためなら　私は何だってする
この町のすべてを敵に回しても
Even if it involves making this
entire city my enemy, I won't stop!
やめるわけにはいかないんだ
Hey!
ちょっと
What is that?
何　あれ
A fetus?
胎児
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない　意味無い！
この能力が光散らす　その先に遥かな想いを
チカラ
歩いてきた　この道を　振り返ることしか
出来ないなら…今ここで全てを壊せる
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
加速するその痛みから
誰かをきっと守れるよ
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
身体中を　光の速さで　駆け巡った　確かな予感
掴め！望むものなら残さず　輝ける自分らしさで
信じてるよ　あの日の誓いを
この瞳に光る涙　それさえも強さになるから
Damn it's not working.
ダメですわ
All the cameras are dead!
どのカメラも死んでしまってますの
電話も繋がらない
The phones won't work either!
Wait up!
待ちなさい
I can't leave Onee-sama all alone!
お姉様をほっておけませんわ
What can you do with those injuries?
そのケガで何ができるっていうの
でも
But...
Believe in Misaka-san.
御坂さんを信じなさい
She will surely be fine.
彼女ならきっと
A fetus?
胎児
Metamorphose...
<Metamorphose>
肉体変化
I never heard of an ability like that.
こんな能力　聞いたこと
What?!
What is that?
何　あれ　大きくなってる
It's getting bigger!
Misaka-san!
御坂さん
Uiharu-san, why are you...!
初春さん　なんで
Uiharu-san, are you all right?
初春さん　大丈夫
Oh, yes. Umm...
はい　あの
ダメじゃない
You shouldn't have come down here!
こんな所に下りてきちゃ
ごめなさい
I-I'm sorry!
But...
でも
そこから出ないで
Don't come out from behind there!
I don't really get it, but if I have to fight it, I will!
よく分かんないけど
やるってんなら 相手に
追ってこない
He wont chase me?
Is he just being violent without a purpose?
闇雲に暴れてるだけなの
It's like something is hurting him...
まるで　何かに苦しいんでるみたい
What's the matter?
どうした
It's the patients! They've suddenly started going violent!
それが　例の患者さんたちが急に暴れ出して
Did they regain conciousness?
意識が戻ったのか
いいえ　さっきまで眠ったままだったのが
No, they were asleep, but just now, all at once, they...
一斉に
At once?
All the patients are having the same sympthoms.
他の患者さんたちも　同じ症状を示しているんです
Even though they are still unconscious,
it's like a bad dream is frightening them.
意識は戻ってないのに　まるで　悪い夢に苛まれているような
What in the world is happening?
一体　何が起こっているんだ
Hey, what is this?
おい　何だよこりゃ
Get back.
Some monster?
怪獣だよ
Is this some biological weapon somebody developed?
どっかの生物兵器か
We have utilize anyone who can still move to stop it.
動けるものだけでもやるしかないじゃんよ
I'm authorizing the use of live ammunition!
実弾の使用許可する
Fire!
撃て
なんか　大きくなってる
I-Is it getting bigger?!
It's amazing.
すごいな
I didn't expect a monster like this to be born.
まさかあんな化け物が生まれるとは
If I presented this to an academic
committee, I'd surely receive an award.
学会に発表すれば表彰ものだ
The network is already out of my control,
もはやネットーワークは私の手を離れ
and there is no way to get them back or cure them.
あの子たちを取り戻すことも回復させることも叶わなくなったか
It's all over.
お仕舞いだな
Please don't give up!
諦めないでください
This is from the AIM diffusion field?
AIM拡散力場の
I suspect it's a collection of it.
おそらく集合体だろう
そうだな
Well yeah, for now, we'll call it "AIM Burst".
<AIM Burst>
仮に幻想猛獣とでも呼んでおこうか
The AIM diffusion field from 10,000 people collected by Level Upper became a catalyst,
<Level Upper>
幻想御手のネットワークによって束ねられた　一万人のAIM拡散力場
allowing a monster created from their semi-consciousnesses to appear.
それらが触媒となって生まれた潜在意識の怪物
言い換えれば
In other words, you could call it a
lump of 10,000 people's emotions.
あれは一万人の子どもたちの思念の塊だ
I was supposed to make my dream come true in this city.
この町で　俺は夢を叶えるはずだった
My dream of becoming a ability user...
能力者になるという夢を
Yet...
だけど
My dream was only a dream!
夢は夢でしかなかった
However much I tried,
どんなに努力を続けようと
this obstacle called "talent" always gets in the way in this city.
この町では才能という壁が邪魔をする
惨めな日常だけが残った
A pitiful existence is all that remains.
Days of being stepped on and days of my misery being ignored...
踏みつけにされ　見て見ぬふりをされるという日常だけが
If that's the case, then...
だったら
the only hope I have is to obtain that.
手に入れるしかないじゃないか
No matter what I do, I have to obtain that power.
どんなことをしても
力を手に入れるしかないじゃないか
It's really sad...
なんか　かわいそう
How can we stop it?
どうすればあれを止めることができるの
You're asking me that?!
それは私に聞くのかい
Whatever I tell you now, you won't bele-
今の私が何を言っても
君たちは信
私の手錠
You removed my handcuffs, right?
木山先生が外してくれたんですよね
Huh?
I was just acting on a whim.
ただの気まぐれさ
まさかそんなことで私を信用すると
Are you telling me that is enough for you to trust me?
それに
Also...
there's no way you're going to lie when you want to save those children.
子どもたちを助けるのに　木山先生が嘘つくはずありません
I believe you.
信じます
I belive in you, sensei.
先生のこと信じてるもん
Huh?
Did you hear about it?
聞いてたの
Geez...
まったく
AIM burst is a monster born from the Level Upper's network.
<AIM Burst><Level Upper>
幻想猛獣は幻想御手のネットワークが生み出した怪物だ
Maybe we can stop it by destroying the network.
ネットワークを破壊すれば止められるかもしれない
The Level Upper cure program!
幻想御手の治療プログラム
It's worth a try.
試してみる価値はあるはずだ
I'll deal with this.
あいつは私が何とかするから
In the meantime, go give that to Antiskills, Uiharu-san!
<Antiskill>
初春さんはその間にそれを持って警備員の所へ
Understood!
分かりました
It's problematic when there are so many people who
are willing to believe other people without a reason...
本当に　根拠もなく人を信用する人間が多くて困る
Captain!
隊長
No! Don't come near!
いっ　いや　来ないで
いっ　いや
Nooooooooooooooooooo!
Why were you just standing there?
何ぼやっとしてんだよ
I can't stop you from dying!
死んでも知らないわよ
あっ　あなた誰
Wh-Who are you?
What is a ordinary civilian doing here?
一般人がこんな所で何してるの
Geez.
ったく
I'm tired of everyone calling me a ordinary civilian!
どいつもこいつも一般人　一般人って
You have to hurry and escape or...
とにかく　すぐにここから逃げなっ
逃げるのはそっち
You're the ones who need to run.
It won't approach us unless we attack!
あいつはこっちが攻撃しなきゃ寄ってこないんだから
それでも
Even so, we can't retreat.
撤退するわけにはいかないんじゃん
あれが何だか分かるか
Do you know what that is?
原子力実験炉じゃん
It's an Experimental Nueclear Reactor.
Seriously?
へっ　マジ
What is she doing?
何やってんの　あの子
That's...
あれは
the girl who Kiyama was holding hostage!
木山の人質になっていた
Damn she must have failed to escape in this chaos...
この混乱で逃げ遅れてるじゃん
That's not true.
違う
Uiharu-san is neither a hostage nor a victim who failed to escape.
初春さんはもう　人質でも逃げ遅れてるんでもない
頼みがあるの
I have a favor to ask you.
I'm your opponent!
アンタの相手はこの私よ
Hey!
Damn it!
ったく　少しは人の話を
Listen to what other people have to say for once!
Oh shit!
やばい
Ouch...
よかった
What a relief it hasn't been destroyed.
壊れてない
I have to hurry or...
急がないと
It'll be too late for everyone.
みんな　手遅れに
I'm judgement too!
<Judgement>
私だって　風紀委員なんだから
I'm going to save everyone...
みんなを
And Saten-san, too!
佐天さんを
Are you all right?
大丈夫
Geez...
まったく
Kids these days sure are reckless.
最近の若いのは無茶するじゃん
Is the cure program okay?
治療プログラムは
It's safe.
無事です
We will defend you!
掩護するじゃん　速く
Hurry!
Damn it!
っくそ　また
Again?
Don't keep ignoring me.
しかとしてんじゃないよ
I told you, I'm your opponent.
アンタの相手はこの私だって言ったでしょ
Quit being a crybaby and face me directly!
みっともなく泣き叫んでないで
まっすぐ私に向かって来なさい
幻想猛兽
A Certain Scientific Railgun
AIM
Burst
ワクチンソフトが学園都市中に流すことで
By spreading the vaccine software throughout Academy City,
幻想御手のネットワークを破壊する
we should be able to destroy the Level Upper network.
花飾りの少女が上手くやれば
If that girl with the flower decorations succeeds,
幻想猛獣の暴走を抑えることができるはずだ
we should be able to stop the AIM Burst's rampage.
だが
However...
There really is no end!
ほんと　きりがないわね
ったく
Geez!
Why do you have to head for the nuclear facility?!
何だって　原子力の施設なんかに向かって来るのよ
怪獣映画かっつーの
Is this some monster movie?!
こうなったら
There's no other choice...
あれは一万人の子どもたちの
That's the 10,000 children's...
まずっ
Oh shit!
しまった
That's right!
ああそうじゃ
時間がない
There's no time left!
これから転送する音声ファイルをあらゆる手段を使って学園都市に流せ
Use every possible means to spread this sound file through the city.
転送完了しました
Transfer is complete!
I'll take responsibilty,
責任は私が持つ
とにかく流すじゃん
so just broadcast it!
これは
This is...
先生　患者さんたちが
Doctor, the patients...
こっから先は
I can't let you go any further, but...
絶対に通すわけにはいかないんだけど
What is this song?
何　この曲
Oh shit!
やばっ
っくそ
Damn...
いくらやってもすぐに再生するんじゃ意味が
It's useless for me to keeping trying if it's able to regenerate immediately.
再生しない
It isn't regenerating?
この曲　治療プログラム
This song is the cure program!
Uiharu-san must have done it!
初春さんやったんだ
悪いわね
Too bad.
これでゲームオーバーよ
Game over now!
間一髪って奴
That's what we call a close call.
気を抜くな
Don't get too complacent!
It's not over yet!
まだ終わっていない
Hey!
ちょっ　なんでこんな所に
Why are you here?
No way...
そんな
ネットワークの破壊には成功しても
Even though the network was sucessfuly destroyed,
あれはAIM拡散力場が生んだ一万人の思念の塊
this is the mass of ten thousand people's
emotions born from the AIM Diffusion Field.
普通の生物の常識は通用しない
What we consider normal for other living organisms does not apply to this!
話が違うじゃない
You didn't tell me that!
Then what can I do?
だったらどうしろって
核が
There should be a core.
力場を固定させている核のようなものが　どこかにあるはずだ
Something like a core holding the field together.
It should be somewhere.
それを破壊すれば
If you destroy that...
なんかな
Am I...
佐天さん
Saten-san?
<Level 0>
無能力者って欠陥品
Level Zeros are defective products.
だと思ってやがる
People seem to think this,
のが許せない
and I can't stand it.
It's no use.
ダメだって
Level Zeros are...
<Level 0>
無能力者って
これは
This is...
毎日は
How miserable each day is.
どんだけ惨めだったか
あなたにはわからないでしょけど
You can't understand, but,
there are times when expectations like that hurt.
その期待が
重い時もあるんですよ
下がって
Stand back.
巻き込まれるわよ
You'll get caught in crossfire.
構うものか　私にはあれを生み産み出した責任が
I don't care!
I have to take responsibility for giving birth to that-
アンタがよくても アンタの教え子はがどうすんの
Even if you don't care about yourself, what about your students?
回復した時 あの子たちが見たいのは　アンタの顔じゃないの
Isn't it your face the one they would want to see when they are cured?
こんなやり方しないなら 私も協力する
I'll help you, if you choose some other method.
そう簡単に諦めないで
So, don't give up so quickly.
あとね
And also...
It's not going to hit you...
あいつに巻き込まれるんじゃない
私が巻き込んじゃうって　言ってんのよ
What I'm saying is that I might hit you.
It's using the same type of dielectric polarization field I used.
あれは　私が使用したものと同じ誘電力場
やはり　彼女の力では
With her power she won't be able...
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
hanate! kokoro ni kizanda yume o, mirai sae okizari ni shite
Fire away! Leave behind the future and the dreams engraved in your heart
電撃は直撃していない
The electric shock isn't hitting directly?
未来さえ置き去りにして
だが 強引に捩じ込んだ電気抵抗の熱で
However, the surface of the body is being destroyed by the heat of the electrical conduction resistance.
限界など知らない 意味無い！
genkai nado shiranai imi nai!
It knows no limits and has no meaning
体の表面が消し飛んでいく
この力が光り散らす
kono chikara ga hikari chirasu, sono saki ni haruka na omoi o
My power will radiate these distant feelings
She wasn't fighting seriously with me?
あたしと戦った時のあれは
その先に遥かな想いを
全力ではなかったのか
歩いてきた
aruitekita, kono michi o, furikaeru koto shika
If I can only look back on this path that I tried to walk
この道を
振り返ることしか
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
出来ないなら
dekinai nara...ima koko de subete o kowaseru
I could destroy it all here and now
Everyone...
ダメだって
今ここで
wanted...
能力者に
全てを壊せる
なりたかった
to be a ability user.
気づいてあげられなくて
I was unable to notice it.
暗闇に堕ちる街並み
kurayami ni ochiru machinami, hito wa doko made tachimukaeru no?
The streets descend into darkness
しょうがないよね
Nothing could be done, right?
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの
あたしには何も
Since I don't have anything-
I expended a lot of effort.
加速するその痛みから
kasoku suru sono itami kara, dareka o kitto mamoreru yo
How far will people go to resist? I'm sure I'll be able to protect someone from this worsening pain
誰かをきっと守れるよ
You wanted to try hard, right?
頑張りたかったんだよね
I hated myself because I didn't have any power.
何の力もない自分がいやで
hakanaku mau musuu no negai wa
The infinite wishes that dance transiently
儚く舞う 無数の願いは
でも　どうしても憧れは捨てられなくて
However I still couldn't stop admiring and wanting it.
この両手に 積もってゆく
kono ryoute ni tsumotteyuku
Will gather in my hands
うん　でもさ
Yes.
切り裂く闇に 見えてくるのは
Then let's try once more again.
kirisaku yami ni miete kuru no wa
To see into the cutting darkness
だったら　もう一度頑張ってみよう
重く深く 切ない記憶
omoku fukaku setsunai kioku
Is a heavy, deep painful memory
色褪せてく 現実に揺れる
You don't have to worry, now.
こんな所で くよくよしてないで
iroaseteku genjitsu ni yureru
Cowering in a faded reality
絶望には 負けたくない
zetsubou ni wa maketaku nai
I dont want to lose to despair
Don't lie to yourself.
自分で自分に嘘つかないで
私が今 私であること
watashi ga ima watashi de aru koto
Right now I am myself
Once again!
もう一度
胸を張って 全て誇れる
mune o hatte subete hokoreru!
I'll stick out my chest and be proud of it all!
Looking！The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Looking!
The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it.今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. imasugu
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it now
身体中を光の速さで
karadajuu o hikari no hayasa de
A certain premonition that ran through my body
This is...
これが
駆け巡った 確かな予感
kakemegutta tashika na yokan
at the speed of light
Level Five.
<Level 5>
超能力者
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
hanate! kokoro ni kizanda yume o, mirai sae okizari ni shite
Fire away! Leave behind the future and the dreams engraved in your heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
限界など知らない 意味無い！
genkai nado shiranai imi nai!
It knows no limits and has no meaning
この力が光り散らす
kono chikara ga hikari chirasu, sono saki ni haruka na omoi o
My power will radiate these distant feelings
その先に遥かな想いを
実験用炉心及びその周辺設備の点検　終了しました
We have finished checking out...
the experimental nuclear reactor...
and the surrounding equipment.
共に異常ありません
We find nothing out of ordinary.
了解
Understood.
Check again to see if there are any casualties around the facility.
施設周辺にケガ人がいないか　もう一度チェックして
あの
Umm...
その どうするの　子どもたちのこと
Well...
What are you going to do about the kids?
I have no intention of giving up, of course.
勿論諦めるつもりはない
Huh?
もう一度やり直すさ
I'll just start over again.
刑務所だろうと世界の果てだろうと
Whether I'm in prison or at the end of the world.
私の頭脳はここにあるのだから
My brain is still in here.
However, I have no intention of
choosing only honorable methods.
ただし
今後も手段を選ぶつもりはない
気に入らなければその時はまた
If you don't like it, then you'll end up getting in my way again.
邪魔しに来たまえ
やれやれ　懲りない先生だわ
Geez.
A teacher like that doesn't give up.
お姉 さまぁー！
Onee-sa
Oh, Kuroko.
黒子
ma~!
黒子は心配しましたのよ
I was so worried.
心を痛めておりましたのよ
My heart was aching!
御髪に乱れが
Your hair is all messed up!
There are countless scratches on your skin!
お肌に無数の擦り傷が
どうやら電撃を放つ体力も残ってないご様子
It looks like you don't even have enough power left to shock me.
ここは黒子が隅々まで見て擦って癒してあげますの
This is the chance for me to examine you and touch you everywhere... and heal you.
Oh yeah, that's right.
そうですわ
先程病院から連絡がありましたの
I recieved a notice from the hospital just now.
幻想御手の使用者たちが 次々と意識を取り戻していると
The Level Upper users are regaining conciousness one after another.
あなたのおかげですわよ　初春
It's all thanks to you, Uiharu.
っというわけで お姉様
So then, Onee-sama!
What are you doing!
Get out of my way!
佐天さん
Saten-san!
よう　初春
Yo, Uiharu!
This is no place for you!
ようっじゃないですよ
I looked all over because I couldn't find you in your hospital room.
病室にいないから探したじゃないですか
Is it okay for you to be up?
起き上がって大丈夫なんですか
またどっか具合が悪いとか
Aren't you feeling bad somewhere?
ちょっと眠ってただけだもん
I was just taking a nap.
I feel like myself again, now.
すっかり元通り
Even the part about being not having any ability.
能力が使えない所までね
Huh?
佐天さん
Saten-san?
ごめん
I'm sorry.
つまんないことに拘って
I cared too much about needless things.
内緒でズルして
I secretly cheated...
初春をこんな目に合わせて
and made you go through all this.
そんなこと
It wasn't like that.
あたし　もう少しで
I almost lost something much more important than any ability.
能力なんかよりずっと大切なものを 無くすどころだった
そうだ　忘れてた
Oh yeah...
I forgot about it.
I'm back!
たっだいま
Just a little more time
病み上がりの癖に 何するんですか
Y-You just recovered from a disease!
What are you doing?!
Let's stay together my friend
Let's stay together, my friend
快気祝い 快気祝い
It's to congratulate you on your recovery!
それにしても
But anyways, Uiharu, your panties are...
Wont' you tell me why
Won't you tell me why
And our case is solved.
これにって一件落着ですわね
Let me know what makes you cry
Yes.
どうかなさいまして
Is something bothering you?
One day in your life
Oh... No, nothing.
何でも
Don't you know things can change my friend
Don't you know things can change, my friend
幻想御手を使った人たちって本当に間違ってたのかな
The people who used Level Upper, was it really wrong for them to do so?
Won't you dry your eyes
Maybe it was us ability users who didn't notice them.
結局あの人たちの気持ちに気づいてあげられなかった
Someday you will find your light
私たち能力者が今回の事件をまねった張本人なんじゃないかな
Maybe we were the actual ones who caused this whole incident.
Shining jumping singing dreaming growing...
Shining, jumping, singing, dreaming, growing...
大方　そんなことを考えてはありませんの
Isn't that what you're thinking?
So just the way you are
Don't copy me. You're disgusting.
真似しないでよ　気持ち悪い
Here's my heart no need to hurry
Here's my heart, no need to hurry
お姉様らしい優しさですわ
It's because you're really kind.
優しさついでにもう一つ気づいてほしいことがありますの
I have something similar to your kindness that you might want to notice.
Cause no one can take away your right
'Cause no one can take away your right
それは　黒子の　気　持　ち
That is...
In every case you can break througe
In every case, you can break through
My feelings!
Realize, I think of you
Realize I think of you
ありがとう　黒子
Thank you Kuroko.
相も変わらないアンタの変態ぶりに私もやっと調子が出てきたわ
Your perverseness that never seems to
change is getting me back to usual again!
Here's your heart no need to worry
Here's my heart, no need to worry
だって佐天さんは
Saten-san you are!
The stars above shine bright in the night
The stars above, shine bright in the night
Oh you!
Why you!
Just call my name if you're feeling blue
Misaka-san!
御坂さん
白井さん　大丈夫ですか
Shirai-san, are you okay?
相変わらず元気ね
Cheer up I'll be with you
You never change, do you?
Cheer up, I'll be with you
Here's your heart I'm not feeling lonely
Here's your heart, I'm not feeling lonely
We can make it hope our dreams will all come true
We can make it, and hope our dreams will all come true
Go on smile for you and me
Go on, smile for you and me
For...
You and me
Next Episode
っていうか　一山超えたら水着会とか安くない
Isn't it rather cheap to use a swimsuit episode after one arc is over?
比基尼很引人注目
不过连衣裙很能
衬出身体的线条
只适合苗条的人穿
With a bikini, people just
see the top and bottom, but
with a one-piece, the whole
bodyline shows, so only
slender people look
good in it
何おっしゃいますの　お客様は神様ですのよ
What are you saying?
The customers are gods you know!
黒子のあんな姿やこんな姿…
Kuroko dressed like this and that-
見たくない
I don't want to see it!